Pope Joan is a drama, history, romance film directed by Sönke Wortmann.
A 9th century woman of English extraction born in the German city of Ingelheim
disguises herself as a man and rises through the Vatican ranks.
Pope Sergius II., played by John Goodman.
Johanna von Ingelheim, played by Johanna Wokalek.
Gerold, played by David Wenham.
Village Priest, played by Iain Glen.
Aesculapius, played by Edward Petherbridge.
Anastasius, played by Anatole Taubman.
Pope Joan (German: Die Päpstin) is a 2009 epic historical drama film produced by Bernd Eichinger, based on
American novelist Donna Woolfolk Cross' novel of the same name about the legendary Pope Joan.
Directed by Sönke Wortmann, it stars Johanna Wokalek as Joan, David Wenham
as Gerold, her lover, and John Goodman as Pope Sergius II.
The film's world premiere occurred in Berlin on 19 October 2009, with
its general release in Germany on 22 October 2009.
The film explores themes of germany, empowerment,
vatican (holy see), pope, 9th century.
The tone is emotional.